YASH AHUJA

CONTACT

- Thane, Maharashtra, India
- (+91) 7208896589
- yashahuja1296@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/sam16
- github.com/samsoul16

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ◆ Android Development : Java, Core, Kotlin
- ◆ Languages : C#, Clojure, ClojureScript, Emacs Lisp, Java, Adv. Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- ◆ Tools: Unity3D, Firebase, Vuforia Sdk, Mapbox Sdk, Facebook API, Google API, Google Maps API, Instamojo API, Spacemacs, Orgmode
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite3, MsSQL
- ◆ Frameworks & Libraries : React Native, Expo, Materialize, re-frame, re-frisk, ReactNavigation, SemanticUI, Material Design Support Library

SOFT SKILLS

- Creative and Innovative problem solver
- Always love to lead people by example
- A great team player, believe in team output; total team output is always greater than personal output
- ◆ Responsible and Reliable person in times of need.
- ◆ Can handle release pressures and still deliver on time
- Eager and quick to learn new technologies and other things
- A great student and love to teach / share knowledge to peers / partners

¥ SUMMARY

A creative person always flooded with innovative ideas; an enthusiastic, quick and eager learner, with lots of love and experience in mobile development (Android + React Native), trying to solve real word problems with the aid of mobile technology available to masses on their fingertips.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Published 2 Papers in Springer (ICTIS 2017 and ICTCS2017).
- Analysed FB Data and Airline Schedules in Data Analytics using R Programming in Summer School of July 2016.
- Being the Core Organizer of Lan Gaming Committee of our TechFest PRAXIS un 2014, '15 and '16 brought the highest number of participants and highest income (50% of the total fest income) from a single portfolio while managing the first ever biggest Lan Gaming Committee (45+ members) in 2016.
- Created unique fun events and also rebuilt the ISTE V.E.S.I.T. App during my tenure as a member of Planning & Management (PnM) Cell of ISTE VESIT in 2015-16.
- Made an aggregator type business model to solve the social issue of students not getting proper counselling and pitched it to major VCs(Google including) when I was a part of the first ever India's Next 40 Entrepreneurial course in Jul-Aug 2015.
- Was one of the few initial member who kicked off the development of Roms and Themes for Samsung Galaxy Y Duos at xda-developers in 2011, '12 and '13.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNITY3D GAME DEVELOPER AND DESIGNER

Mar 2018 - Present

MINDSEED

Immerz Math: An AR & GPS based game to teach the importance and the relevance of Mathematics in real life to students and break the stigma that mathematics is tough and remove its fear.

- Build a game from Scratch using Unity3d using Vuforia, Mapbox Sdks and Google & Fb APIs
- Launched a pilot release for 30 students in April
- Implemented Multiplayer team mechanics for missions to encourage teamwork and competition
- Able to trace student locations and make vaults visible only at specified locations
- Generated Reports based on using Unity provided and data Analytics

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jul 2017 - Feb 2018

MINDSEED

Immerz English: A cross-platform app which was coupled with a physical kit to aid parents teach their children English and enhance their communication skills.

- Built from scratch a cross-platform app in bleeding edge technology React Native with open source tool-chain Expo
- Written whole code in functional programming language clojure & clojurescript supported by Mongodb databases
- Implemented In-App purchases using InstaMojo Payment
- Integrated OTP, email and login using Fb & Google APIs.
- Generated student learning curve reports from the analytics of data collected

YASH AHUJA

CONTACT



(+91) 7208896589

yashahuja1296@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/sam16

github.com/samsoul16

EDUCATION

♦ B.E in Computer Science V.E.S. Institute of Technology, **Mumbai University**

♦ H.S.C in Science K.C. College, Churchgate, Maharashtra State Board

PUBLICATIONS

"En-SPDP: Enhanced Secure Pool **Delivery Protocol" For Food Delivery System** Information And Communication **Technology For Intelligent Systems** (ICTIS 2017) - Volume 2

♦ Performance Analysis Of "En-SPDP: **Enhanced Secure Pool Delivery Protocol**" For Food Delivery Network

Information and Communication **Technology for Competitive** Strategies (ICTCS 2017)

INTERESTS









₱ PROJECTS

POOL DELIVERY SYSTEM: **RESTAURANT FOOD DELIVERY**

Jul 2016 - May 2017

B.E. Final Year Project.

- Developed a Location Based Pooling Algorithm for our Pool Delivery System
- Created an enhanced custom version of S.E.T. Protocol consisting of 9 different phases
- Created 3 Android Apps Customer, Hotel & Delivery to be given to different clients
- The whole system was backed by php-myadmin backend

I.S.T.E. V.E.S.I.T

Jul 2015

SYSTEM

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- The official app of I.S.T.E. helps users knows about the on-going activities, events, scores, leaderboards and updates of the Society in VESIT
- Rebuilt from scratch the whole app
- Revamped the whole UI following material design guidelines Published in Google Play

MY WEATHER

Apr 2016

INDIVIDUAL

- Weather App to fetch current weather of entered location from openweatherapi.com
- Learnt the concept of JSON Parsing & data retrieving.

POKETPA

Aug 2017

INTERNSHIP

- Personal Assistant App which shows all the events happening nearby
- Created a vertical view pager to show events fetched from online data source with categories

SAM: SIMPLE ANDROID MEMO

Mar 2016

INDIVIDUAL

- An app for creating, editing and sharing text Memo's
- Explored SQLite3 to store user data
- Implemented color themes on per Memo basis

NOTEPAD

Mar 2016

B.E. M.C.C Project

- A Simple Notepad App for creating, fetching, deleting, editing simple text files
- Also provided the feature of exporting text files in a specified location in storage.

STUDYLEAGUE

Sep 2015

EXTERNAL

- Designed UI interface for the Android app
- Developed a prototype for the same in Android Studio following Material Design Guidelines

ORMS: ONLINE RETAIL **MANAGEMENT SYSTEM**

Jul 2015 - Apr 2016

B.E. THIRD YEAR PROJECT

- Sem 5: Developed a simple website for managing retailer accounts, stocks, bills etc. using HTML, CSS AND JS.
- Sem 6: Carried forward the same project to create a Distributed DB System and learn its concepts







